sawadika
I came to Bangkok, Thailand
Bangkok is a city with a unique culture
There are also rich delicacies
Come with me to start a delicious journey in Bangkok
It's so busy when I come to this place now
This is the largest farmers market in Bangkok
Khlongtoei Market
This market is not only big
The most important thing is that it is open 24 hours a day
Why is it open 24 hours?
It’s because there are many catering businesses
they need to come to this market to purchase goods in the middle of the night
And it’s a locals’ market
This is all in Thai
It’s probably difficult to communicate with you in English here
no tourists
So lively
Let's take a look
Look how interesting this drink is
The color is very nice
There are also eldest sister’s pancakes
spring cake
various dishes
The dishes are arranged neatly and it’s very healing
All kinds of meat
neatly
I want to buy everything when I come here
And it's not expensive
vegetable area
meat section
There is also a fruit section over there
So lively
This feels great
Market atmosphere
This is a fish seller
Catfish
All are live fish
So interesting
You get a bag
Just picking up fish can pick up a bag
This row is full of fish
It fell to the ground at every turn
At first glance, no one, took it
So crowded
My favorite thing about this market
It's all food and everything
all prices are clearly marked
why
This has something to do with Thai Buddhism
Why are they Buddhist?
Just because there are so many types
they can't remember the price either
Then there are people who clearly mark the price
transparent
How much money is how much money
The key interesting thing is
its price is per kilogram
Because the whole of Thailand is calculated by kilogram
When you come here, pay attention, these are two pounds
There are many sellers of cooked food in this market
Mainly barbecue
Various kebabs
I think this is good
grilled sausages
very unique
This sausage is a delicacy from the Isan region in northeastern Thailand
This shelf is particularly interesting
It's placed diagonally
In order to drip this oil
Sausage, Glutinous Rice Sausage
this
two
This should also be dipped in sauce
Look at this sausage, it's all burnt and crispy
It looks delicious
tasty
Here is glutinous rice
pork
Coriander root and garlic
The most important thing is that it is slightly sour
Some of this kind of sausages have been fermented
This is fermented and sour
Some are not fermented
There is no sour taste
Have some dipping sauce
Mixed dipping sauce
This sauce is good
Another little chili
It's too spicy
green chili
This is the Grand Palace in Bangkok, Thailand
It has a history of more than 300 years
The Grand Palace is the palace of the Thai royal family
Usually available for tourists to visit
If there are some royal ceremonies or activities
held right here
The Grand Palace was built during the reign of King Rama I
However, it was later repaired and expanded by many generations of kings
Now comes the era of Rama X
The scenery here is really beautiful
You must visit this place when you come to Bangkok, Thailand
There is a group of murals worth admiring in the Grand Palace
And this mural is very famous
Known as one of the longest murals in the world
How long is it
A full 2 ​​kilometers
right behind me
Very exquisite
What is the content of this mural?
The content is taken from an Indian epic
called Ramayana
In Thailand, it’s called “Ramajan”
The content is the same as Ramayana
Rama is a prince
He wants to inherit the throne
But at this time, he was framed by his stepmother
Exiled in the forest for more than ten years
in the process of exile
His wife was also snatched away by a demon king
This time he was with his brother
and with the help of the monkey god Hanuman
defeated the devil and rescued his wife
and returned to the country to inherit the throne
Although this story sounds quite simple
but whether in India or Thailand
are very influential
For example, there is a drama in Thailand now called Kong Opera
This is the show
This Confucius Opera is equivalent to our domestic Peking Opera
very famous
So exquisite
close look
Let’s not talk about this painting skills
We don't understand either
The key is in its details
Look at this naked kid
And this
There's also kissing here
This is the image of the monkey god
Have a long tail
This monkey is actually the prototype of Sun Wukong in "Journey to the West"
But Sun Wukong uses a golden cudgel
Sun Wukongis going too
This is a sword
So shocking
Thailand is a Buddhist country
Elements about Buddhism can be seen everywhere in the streets and alleys
The place I am coming to now is called Wat Pho
There is a very big reclining Buddha here
It can be said to be the largest reclining Buddha in Thailand
Why does this Buddha lie down in this form?
It is said that this is the posture of Sakyamuni when he attained nirvana
I saw this gesture
I think of Thai people's character
Very lazy and comfortable look
Go to this bed
Very shocking
Come and try the very famous curry rice on the streets of Bangkok
This restaurant has been on Netflix
Appeared on many food programs
Next up is "Axing Chinese Food Tour"
Several large pots of curry
This is the local work meal
one serving
red and green, mix
these two
Yes
an egg
ok
sausage
Thanks
This restaurant is interesting
Very marketable
One person, one stool, no table
It feels a bit like eating noodles in Chongqing
The one I ordered is a combination of green curry and red curry
This has some fried sausages added to it
And a braised egg
If you think it's not spicy enough
There's also chili
And fish sauce
And vinegar and these sauces
Smells very good
The staple food of Thai people is rice
Thai people greet each other a bit like Chinese people
Chinese people say, have you eaten?
Thai people say, have you eaten rice?
Try this green curry first
This green curry contains fish balls
This should be a radish
This is lime leaf
Try the fish balls
I saw there was a lot of curry sauce inside
looks very rich
A little spicy
The taste of curry is actually quite bland
You see, this soup feels quite thick
But it tastes lighter
good
Why is it bland?
Maybe it’s because of the addition of radish
This is not aradish
Winter melon that looks like a radish
tasty
Add some sausage
Crispy fried sausages
Why is green curry this color?
Just because it has green chili in it
Lemongrass and kaffir lime leaves
So green is produced
What about red? Look at this red curry
It's because it has nutmeg in it
And red chili
Let’s try this red one
This red one has a stronger taste
There are three types of curry in Thailand
One is green and one is red
and yellow
Yellow is the original curry
Because curry itself contains turmeric
This red one is so spicy
These three types of curry in Thailand are yellow, green and red
It also corresponds to the cooking ingredients
Green curry is usually fish
this is fish cakes and fish balls
Or chicken
why
Just because it tastes a little spicier
Slightly spicy
A stronger red curry is to cook beef and mutton
why
Beef and mutton have a bit of fishy smell
Then ordinary yellow curry is just cooking pork
It's all very particular
Mine is beef
Red curry beef
Moreover, the taste of curry is different in each region of Thailand
Roughly divided into northern, central and southern
Let’s see what kind of curry you eat
I know where you are from
This is a bit like Shaanxi
Northern Shaanxi, Guanzhong, SouthernShaanxi
The taste is different
I can tell where you are from in Shaanxi by looking at the noodles you eat
I like to eat the red one more
spicier
Try the braised eggs
Braised egg is sweet
Curry is actually a seasoning
Just like the Chinese thirteenspice seasoning
It’s the thirteenspice seasoningfrom India
Curry itself is produced in India
But now there are two places that are most famous for eating curry in the world
One is India and the other is Thailand
On the contrary, these years
Thai curry is more popular among international friends
why
I think its taste is more acceptable
And there are many choices
At least these three flavors
sawadika
Look at the traffic jam here
Red
Almost half blocked
The traffic in Bangkok is really congested
Whenever I go out, I have to get stuck in traffic
no matter where you are
As long as it's in the city
It is one of the top ten most traffic-congested cities in the world
But my experience of this fellowship
A bit like the social life of Bangkok people
rhythm of life
How do I say this?
Very confused
Both lazy and slow
Then it’s fast and tense
What are laziness and slowness?
For example, this master drives a car
If I were driving, I would have smashed the steering wheel
He is not in a hurry even if he is blocked
Just drivingslowly
Anyway, there will be a traffic jam for a while and driving for a while
It's like eating noodles on the roadside
Just eat some fried rice and some noodles
It feels very comfortable and lazy
It doesn't cost much
dozens of baht
Fast and tight are what you see on motorcycles outside
woo woo feeling
The population density in this place is also very high
Gives people a feeling of suffocation and nervousness
And the motorcycle goes back and forth very quickly
feeling of speed
Why does it have to be so fast to twist a motorcycle?
This is too many motorcycles
If you don't screw up the floor, people will rush you later
This may be the charm of Bangkok
It's a little better now
Don't be stuck in traffic, we've been stuck in traffic for half an hour
The place I am now is Khao San Road
Very famous in Bangkok
This road is known as a backpacker’s paradise
This road became famous in the 1980s
why
It's because at the earliest time
Now it’s a bar street
In the earliest days, it was a hotel street
It's very cheap for everyone to live here
Especially these European and American backpackers
When traveling to Southeast Asia, Bangkok will be their first stop
In other words, this street is the beginning of their trip to Southeast Asia
The place I am in now is also very interesting
This is traditional Thai culture
religious culture
This is the modern bustling Bangkok
So interesting
When you come here you will see people from all over the world
faces of various countries
hear various languages
This should be in addition to Bangkok International Airport
you can see the places with the most people in each country
So interesting
Let's listen to some music and then gofor a walk
So lively
Let's get high, shall we?
There is an alley next to the main road of Khao San Road
Look at this alley here
All delicious food
And it’s a delicacy eaten by locals
There is a restaurant here
this one
Tom Yum Kung
A must-eat when in Thailand
have a taste
This little restaurant is full, all locals
Tom Yum Kung
Two people?
sawadika
Two people
there
You can sit over there
Or this way
Sit here
How lively here
this is a good place
There is also a Buddha statue behind
Look at this menu
Sloppy
It’s better to order food when you come to Bangkok
why
All have photos
It doesn’t matter if you don’t know how to read
Let’s order some Tom Yum Kung
Stir-fried minced meat with basil leaves
This is a must-eat when you come to Thailand
This is fried egg
I just walked in and saw
There's a big pot frying there and it's very fragrant
Order another shrimp and stir-fried squid
Garlic
Order another fried water spinach
When you come to Thailand, you have to eat fried water spinach
By the way, this is the specialty of Bangkok
It’s a must-eat when you come here
This hot day
Hurry up and have a drink
too cool
Is this table rich?
Began to eat
This bowl of soup is really the real thing
Three big head shrimps
And it’s shelled
And seafood mushrooms
This leaf is amazing
It's kaffir lime leaves
Mainly used to enhance flavor
This leaf gives me the feeling of Tom Yum Kung
And this lemongrass
Also calledscented grass
Probably galangal too
Such a stir
A very strong smell unique to Tom Yum Kung
This one looks like bamboo shoots
This is coconut shoots
We have all eaten bamboo shoots
Coconut shoots are rare
This coconut shoot is the little core inside the coconut tree
Or a young coconut tree that looks like a bamboo shoot
Uncommon ingredients
Tastes a bit like bamboo shoots
It tastes sour and feels like sour bamboo shoots
Same as Guangxi sour bamboo shoots
But it doesn’t stink, just the kind of fresh sour bamboo shoots
tasty
Taste the soup
The taste is too strong
Sour and spicy
And it’s a little sweet
The taste is a balance of salty, sour, spicy and sweet
It seems like every flavor can be equated
delicious
It doesn’t have any weird taste but still tastes good
One bite will give you the feeling of Southeast Asia
But I want to say the most important flavor here
Still smells like lemongrass
Lemongrass is also calledscented grass
This grass can be said to be Thailand’s national grass
It smells like this wherever I go
go to the street
from someone’s yard
or in the room
this is the smell coming out of the kitchen
Entered the hotel lobby
they use this scent as incense in the lobby
can you bear it
If you are very sensitive to this smell
Or you don’t like the taste very much
Then it's over
Because when you stay in a hotel
The shower gel in many hotels also smells like this
What does it taste like?
That's the taste
The meat is full of fresh and sweet taste
and
some Tom Yum Kung soups also add some milk
or put coconut milk in it
This soup is not just for drinking as soup
You can also ladle some soup
some more rice
eat with rice is also a must-have
Tom Yum Kung soup can be said to be the national soup of Thailand
How do I say this?
There are two opinions
One way to say it is
ordinary people eat it almost every day
Too much
There is another theory that during the Thonburi Dynasty
Thailand's Thonburi Dynasty
The princess is sick
Can't eat anything
she can’t even eat pancakes
she don’t like to eat braised noodles either
Anyway, she can’t eat this or that
How to do it
At this time, the king became anxious
Many royal chefs were summoned
Let's find a way
One of the imperial chefs was very courageous
Just raised his hand
I think the princess is not very hungry
This kind of people needs to be pulled out and beheaded
One of them said that I invented a soup
Recently invented
My family all thought it tasted good after eating it
Very appetizing
Sour and spicy
This is the soup
After drinking it for the princess
It tastes great when the princess drinks it
Better than KFC or McDonald's
From then on, this soup was named the national soup by the king
why
Saved the princess' life, right?
Tom Yum Kung in Thai is Tom Yum Kung
How to explain Tom Yum Kung?
divided into three parts
Tom means boiling
It was boiling in the small pot just now
What does Yum mean?
It's a mixture of hot and sour flavors
Tom Yum also has a Kung
Kung is aprawn
There must be prawnin here
What does Tom Yum Kung mean?
very simple
It’s Thai hot and sour soup
That's what people say
If you ask me, this is three prawns soup
Three prawns hot and sour soup
This chili
little chili
No wonder spicy
To be honest, this is not really delicious
I can drink this all by myself without just rice
I forgot that locals cannot lift their bowls when drinking soup
So when you come here, friends, please don’t pick up a bowl and drink from it
Just drink it
Try this fried water spinach
The garlic is not peeled
large cloves of garlic
Very hot
too much sugar
It tastes sweet
Garlic flavor
Then it should have a bit of soy sauce or soybean paste flavor
This dish is influenced by the Chinese
The places where stir-fries are eaten around the world are mainly distributed in Asia
Asian countries
Stir-fried dishes are all influenced by China
especially Thailand
This dish originated from China
There is no such speculation in China
It is too sweet
Put sugar
This dish is not very particular when it is fried at a small roadside stall
How to fry something more particular?
Just chill the water spinach in ice beforehand
I saw some roadside stalls
Just pick up the vegetables from the ice
For example, bean sprouts
For example, water spinach
For example, celery
Or small melons, cucumbers, etc.
Why put it in ice?
Because they want to eat this crispy texture
This dish is fried minced meat with basil leaves
This is basil leaf
ground pork
It also contains little chili and garlic
This dish can be said to be a household name
This is a must-eat dish when you come to Thailand
Tom Yum Kung and stir-fried minced meat with basil leaves
You must eat here
This smell is amazing
First of all, the lean meat is very chewy
Then the fragrance of basil leaves
The most important thing I have to say is
add sugar
all sweet
All are sweet
Friends from Shanghai came here and got used to this taste
It has a bit of soy flavor and a bit of sweetness
Mixed rice should be delicious
Many local people in Bangkok have working meals
Just like when we eat lunch
they must order this dish
Mix this dish with rice
It feels a bit like having a work meal
Still need to add carbohydrates
This fried egg reminds me of the fried eggs in snail rice noodles
Comes withtomato sauce
Same as french fries
I don’t think this egg needs to be dipped intomato sauce
Just eating it tastes delicious
The skin is fried to a crispy texture
Very soft inside
My eyes have been staring at the squid and prawns in position C
Just look at this dish
This looks delicious
Looks like I have an appetite
This dish is good
Why is this dish delicious?
The shrimps and squid are fried first
Full of garlic flavor
Don’t look at this restaurant as a small roadside stall
The taste he makes is quite authentic
Taste of Thai local food
These people are also locals
Because this street is quite far away
Not many tourists come
I think it can be said that everything is delicious
Except that this one and this one are slightly sweet
But some friends like to eat this kind of sweet food